ARCHITECTURE 101
建筑学
- Up all night?
- 整夜无眠？
- Morning, Chief
- 早，Chief
Tired?
困乎？
Ow, my back
哦，额滴背啊！
Gotta let the world know
you worked all night?
想让地球人知道你通宵达旦的工作？
Pretty clever
你太机智了，赞
You changed the floor plan?
你更改了楼层的设计？
Isn't it a bit too flashy?
这是不是太非主流了？
I designed it pretty, didn't I?
我设计的更高大上，不是吗？
Pretty isn't everything
高大上不代表一切！
Clients love this kind of stuff
客户喜欢这种调调，你懂的
The design has to be flashy
to look good
设计要闪光点才好
Go to a sauna,
The meetings at 2 p.m
去洗刷刷，闷个桑拿如何，下午两点不见不散
Why do I have to meet the clients?
为毛我必须要见客户？
You're the designer
你是设计师
Let me get off work
让我先完成手头上的工作
Haven't been home in 2 days
还没宅够两天呢
No smoking in the office!
办公室禁烟,OK!
Second-hand smoking is bad
二手烟很不爽
Think of how much worse
it is for me then
考虑一下现在我的情况多糟糕啊
You have a visitor
你有个访客
Me? Who?
找我？谁？
A friend of yours
你的朋友
My friend? Who?
我基友？谁
How would I know!
我怎么知道
It's been a while
嗯，离开一会
The alumni directory is good
I'm glad I found you
校友指南是个好东西，总是让我找到你了
How've you been?
你何处高就啊
Who... may I ask?
谁……问我吗？
You don't remember me?
你不记得我了？真叫人桑心啊
Well...
额……翠花？！
1st year in college Yang Seo-yeun
大学一年级的Yang Seo-yeun
Back in Jeongneung...
回到Jeongneung
The music major
主修音乐
Oh, right! Yang Seo-yeun!
哦，霍霍，Yang Seo-yeun 思密达啊！
Jeongneungu.
地名（什么鸟地方啊）
What brings you here?
神马风把你吹来了？
How can you forget me?
你居然把我忘了？
I didn't, It's just been so long
是啊，时间太久了
Ages
I didn't change much
我没怎么改变啊
Still, we got older
可是，我们老了
Where do you live?
你住哪？
Gaepo-dong
额，也是个地名
Married?
婚否？
3 years ago
3年了，娃都能打酱油了。
What does your husband do?
你老公那条道上的？
A doctor
医生啦
What's his specialty?
他有什么特点？帅不？
What is this, census?
这是嘛呀，人口普查？
It's Jeju-do
济州岛（有道上居然有）
When can you start?
什么时候开始的？
Start what?
开始什么？
What?
啥？
Why would I come to you?
为什么我会记起你？（不确定是不是这么翻译）
You build houses for a living
你的房子建得不错，像个人住的地方
Build me one
给我建个
Come on
好吗？
I can't
不
Why?
为什么
I've never done this
我还没做完这个
Good, then start with mine
好吧，完事开始我的
Look
好吧，看情况
I'll refer you to someone
who can do it
我介绍一个人，他可以帮助你
A close friend will be better than us
一个铁哥们，比我们做得更好的家伙
Why?
为什么
Is it the money?
因为钱吗？
Of course not
当然不是
Then, do it
那么，帮个忙吧
That's not it. A company has rules
这是两码事。公司有规定
Look
你知道的
The CEO's at the top
我上头呢，有一堆CEO
Then, the manager
然后是经理
Then, there are employees like me
最后才是我们这类底层搬砖的员工
Salary men
一工薪阶级
I can't take just anything
我什么都做不了主
The company won't do it
公司不是不能做
Of course well do it. We appreciate it
而且能做得不错。我相信这点
Lee Seung-min
（人名或地名吧）
It's your first house
这是你的第一个房子？
Do a good job
干得不错
If we start soon, will it
be done before winter?
如果我们马上开始，能够在冬天前完成吗？
Let's go down look around
我们下楼溜溜
Before that
斗胆问一句
Why're you building it?
你为什么建造这房子？
What do you mean?
你想知道什么？
A rich woman like you?
有富婆包养你，霍霍？
Why insist on building
a house down on an island?
为什么执着在一个岛上建房子？
For what?
为啥？
The air is nice
空气清新啊
Your husband must make a lot
to build a house anywhere
你丈夫一定话费很多时间来在各处建造房子？
It's investing?
这算投资吗？
Right, Jeju-do is a hot spot
没错，济州岛是一块热土啊
You can make tons
你可以一夜暴富
You talk so nicely
说的没错
So I'm flaunting money
所以我不差钱
Still, I can rebuild a house
而且，我能建一栋房子
If you don't want to, don't
但是如你不想，对吗？
I'm not begging anyone for anything
我不会乞求任何人任何事
What a waste of my time
浪费我的时间
Here
这
And this
还有这
Why's the reason so important?
为什么这些东西这么重要？
Think I won't pay UP?
认为我木有钱一次付清？
It's not that
不是的
I should know so I can build
a house that suits
我必须知道我建造的房子是适合居住的
I have to know you better
我当然知道你能建造一栋宜人的房子
to make a suitable house
So, you want to know more about me?
那么，你原来进一步了解我吗？
Curious about me?
对我好奇？
After college I tried to become an announcer
毕业我曾努力成为一名播音员
but failed
很遗憾，失败了
So, I just got married
所以呢，找了个饭票
And you?
你呢？
Do you still live in Jeongneung?
你还住在Jeongneung？
Yeah
嗯
How many kids?
多少个小孩？
None yet
还没呢
Why?
嗯哼？
Just somehow, I guess
额，不好说，说来话长
This is my dad's place
这是我老爸的地盘
When he comes out
I want him to live here comfortably
我希望他来这里能住得舒服一些
Is that reason enough?
这理由不充分吧？
It's a mess
总之，一团糟，我也没头绪啊
The framework is fine
这框架结构不错
But it's over 30 years old
但这是30年前的古董设计了
Houses are strong like that
房子坚固如初啊
What's this?
这是什么？
Someone worked on it?
有人在这工作？
Dad wanted to expand
but never finished cuz he got sick
我爸想扩大它但没能完成，因为他生病了
It's been like this since
它曾今是这样的啊
I want it all down
我倒是觉得它完全倒了，重建更合适些
and built new, properly
This is still here?
它还在这？
Dad measured my height here
爸爸在这给我量身高
I was so small
我那时多小啊
My dad made this, too
这也是我爸做的
When I was 6
当我6岁的时候
I stepped on it before it hardened
在它表硬之前我从上面走过
I grew so much
我长地飞快啊
I designed it very flexibly
我将它设计得的很灵活，心中已经有个雏形了
with the sites shape in mind
By putting an atrium inside the house
在房子当中弄个中庭使活动空间看起来更宽敞些
the living space becomes more dynamic
With the skip floor
高低层布局能充分利用空间
the levels are amplified
It adds rhythm to the boxy shape
给方盒子似的屋子增添韵律
and draws in the landscape
且看起来更有诗意
Know what I mean?
能理解我说的吗？
I think this is the solution
我觉得这是个解决方案
- By dividing the space
- 通过分割利用空间
- But...
- 但是……
What?
有什么问题
Why's everything in English?
为什么都是英文？
You don't know
你不懂
but this design is...
这些设计是……
I said, I don't like it
我就是不喜欢这个
Don't try to change me
别试图改变我
But I liked your clothes today
好吧，我还是挺喜欢你的今天的着装的
Except for the tie
除了领带
Really? Don't like my tie?
真的？不喜欢我的领带？
So, my design was like this tie?
哦，我的设计就想这个领带？
Show me what a good tie is then
那么让我瞧瞧所谓的漂亮领带
Still, you've improved a lot
from the old days
好吧，我承认你在就方案上改进了许多
What was Mr. Lee like?
李先生喜欢什么
Ghastly
古板稳重的
Not popular with the girls at all
美女们可不喜欢这个
- Hes still like that
- Hes也喜欢这样
- Really?
- 真的？
You two dating?
你两约会呢？
A duo?
二人组？
How did you two meet?
你们怎么相见的？
I'm curious
我很好奇啊
You had different majors
你们主修不同专业啊
Did you meet on a blind date?
这是你俩初次约会？
Oh, he didn't tell you?
啊，他没告诉你吗？
He chased me around campus
他在学校一直追求我啊
What creative story is that?
一段可歌可泣的故事？
Let's think about Seoul
我们还是聊聊我们呆的地方首尔吧
the city we live in
We eat, drink, go to school
我们吃喝拉撒的地方
and do everything here
But do we really know this city well?
但是我们真的了解这个城市吗？
It's a big place
首尔很大
So, I prepared a map to
我时刻带着地图
Whose beeper is that?
谁的BB机（还有人认识这货不）
Turn it off during class
关掉它
Look. Mark it off like this
看，这样把它关掉
As for me
对我来说
I take bus 38 from here
我坐38路从这地方到这地方
To here
Then here
然后到这
- Focus!
- 小心
- Then I transfer to bus 143
- 然后转143路
Like this
像这样
Then arrive here
最后才到这里
Come up one by one
一个接一个上来
and mark your routes to school
标记你们到学校的路线
You live in Seocho-dong?
你住在Seocho-dong？
Yes, right here
是的，就在这
- Then, wheres Bogwang-dong?
- 那么，Bogwang-dong在哪个旮旯？
- Bogwang-dong?
Is that in Seoul?
那在首尔？
It's here, north of the river
在这，河的北边
Don't you know?
那地方你熟不？
I don't know north of Han River
我对汉河北边不熟，我怕被金三胖看到
You live in Jeongneung?
你住在Jeongneung？
Yes
黑呀
Whos entombed there?
谁躺这下面？
King Jeongjo?
朝鲜的祖先吧？
啊，我不认识？
Jeong Yak-yong?
某人
By next week,please submit a report
下周前，交个报告
Tour around the area you live in
在你这附近溜达溜达
The alleys and buildings you walked past without notice
看看你以前从未留意的大街小巷
Closely examine them
近距离观察它们
And take pictures
然后，拍个照，发个微博什么的
Liking your neighborhood
热爱你的邻里
and understanding it
学会理解它们
That's where architecture starts
这就是建筑学
Understood?
你滴明白？
Jae-wook! Buy me lunch
那谁！给我带份午餐
Do I look like a meal ticket to you?
我看起来像你的长期饭票？
Seniors are supposed to buy juniors food
大的给小的买点吃的是应该的
Who says that?
那个混蛋说的？
- My old tutor
- 我导师
- Hi, Jae-wook!
- 哈罗，Jae-wook!
Seo-yeu n
I'll get g0il'\9
乱码了T0T
How was the class? Not too hard?
课程如何？不是很难吧？
It's okay
马马虎虎
Tell me if you need anything
有什么要帮忙的尽管说
I’ll buy lunch
我要去买午餐了
Take care
小心
Bye
再贱
Who's that?
谁啊？
A music major in our radio club
我们电台俱乐部一搞音乐的
Why's she taking architecture?
她为什么跟建筑打交道了？
Many other majors take this course
很多其他专业的也学这个啊
Many girls, too
也有很多妹纸哦^0^
That's why you are taking this course over?
这就是你学建筑学的原因啊？
Shut up!
滚！
Come over next week
有空的话
and help make a floor model
下周过来帮忙弄个楼层模型
Then, buy us food
顺便买点吃的
Hey!
啊！
Doesn't your mom give you food?
你老妈当年虐待你啊，没给你吃饱？
Does she hate you?
嫌弃你是充话费送的？
Seung-min!
你你你
Hi, Baffle!
- Coming from school?
- 下课了？
- Yeah
- 对啊
- Know that girl?
- 认识那个妹纸？
- What? No.
- 妹纸？不认识
Where'er ya g0il19?
又是乱码，哎
The library, Where else
图书馆在哪？
How's studying?
去自习如何？
Repeating really sucks
复习什么的最烦了
I hate studying
我讨厌学习
And you? Find a girl?
你呢？交到妹纸没？
No, man
还没呢，基友
That's baffling man!
可怜的人啊！
You go to college to date girls!
你来大学就是来约妹纸的！
Who's that? Know the kid?
那是谁？认识那个小萝莉不？
She's no kid, man
不小了，哥们
She's my girlfriend
她是我女朋友
A high school girl?
高中生，真有你的啊？
Who else can a repeater date?
没弄明白
A middle school kid?
初中生啊？
- Fool
- 白痴
- What?
- 什么意思？
What's with your hair college man!
动动你的脑子，大学生！
What?
还是不懂
Use it when you go on blind dates
看我的，初次约会的时候学着点
What is it?
什么？
You need major help, Hold this
你得多学学，拿着
Shake it like this
像这样摇一摇
Then, foam comes out
等到泡沫出来的时候
Then, you put it on your hair like this
然后，像这样抹到你的头发上
- All back straight
- 全反了
- Stupid
- 蠢货
No, you are
对对，就这样
Slick it back, you'll look cool
往后捋捋，帅呆了
- How embarrassing
- 好羞射啊
- See ya
- 对罗，就这样
Man
哥们
Man!
MQm!
帅哥！
Throw out the stuff rotting in fridge
把冰箱里发霉腐烂的东西扔掉
Shut up!
闭嘴！
Come here and help
过来帮帮忙
I have homework
我得写作业
Gotta go
好吧
That little
这么点啊
GUARDIAN TREE
深林守护
Am I out of film? Why isn't it working?
我走出电影了吗？为什么没有效果？
That's odd
很奇怪
Wow, an ant!
嚯哈哈，一只蚂蚁！
You know me, right?
你认识我，对吧？
Pardon?
哈？
Aren't you in Architecture 101 ?
你是不是建筑学101班？
Are you in 1st year?
你第一年就进去了？
Yes
对啊
Architecture major?
主修建筑
Yes
对
Have you lived here long?
你在这住了很长时间？
Yes
没错
HOW long?
多久？
Since I was born
自娘胎以来
So, this is your hometown?
这么说，这是你的家乡了？
Then, you must know the neighborhood well
那么，你应该也知道你邻居了
I just moved here
我刚搬到这
That's an abandoned house
这是间废弃的宅子
- Why?
- 为什么？
- What?
- 啊，什么？
Well, I'm not sure why
好吧，我也搞不明白
Ah, Miss?
额，小姐？
Wait! That's someones house
等等！这是别人的房子
It's trespassing
不要乱闯
It's so pretty
真漂亮
Maybe we shouldn't touch anything
我们最好不好乱动这里的东西
I'm just bringing it back to life
我给这带来了点人气
Wait, Miss
等等，小姐
Sit down
坐
It's so nice
谢谢
By the WHY
话说回来
Why's a music major taking Architecture 101 ?
为什么主修音乐的文艺青年要呆在建筑学101班？
How'd you know that's my major?
你怎么知道我学什么的？
Jae-wook told me in passing
Jae-wook 说口一说，我顺便一听就知道了
He did?
是他啊
How about this?
能说说一二吗？
I'm not an architect major and don't know the area
我不是一个牛逼的建筑师，也不知道这方面的知识
But that's your major and you lived here long
这可是你的主修课啊，而且你住这里这么长时间
So, let's do homework together
那么，一起完成作业吧
That's fair, right?
那个展会，对吗？
How's that fair, Miss?
那个展会怎么样，小姐？
Stop calling me Miss
不要叫我小姐，要叫我女王大人
We're the same age
我们年级相差不大
I will, Miss
是的，女王大人
Let's speak casually, I already am
像平常一样吹吹牛，侃大山，我就是这么随便
You do it, too
你人来熟嘛
Yes, of course
当然，这还用说
Come on!
看着，学着点
I will, Miss
遵命，女王大人
Go ahead
额滴神啊！
I will, Miss. I will
是的，女王大人！遵命
Just do it!
耐克
But we just met
我们不熟
I'll try
我会努力的
This week, let's go to the farthest place
这周我们逛远点
What's the farthest from your home?
离你家最远的地方如何？
What is the definition of far?
多远才算远？
Ever thought of that?
从未去过的？
MQm!
妈妈！
I need this washed and dried
我要洗衣服
How do you expect me to do that?
你想要我做什么？
I gotta wear it, You can do it, Mom
我想穿这件衣服，妈妈
I'm washing up, Have it ready!
我已经洗干净了！
Forget it!
啊，我忘了！
There are 42 stops to Gaepo-dong
42站能到to Gaepo-dong
That's the farthest
好远
I always wondered about
小时候
that place since I was young
我挺向往那地方的
Gaepo-dong
Gaepo-dong?
Isn't it the name of a missile?
不是某种飞弹的名称？
Isn't it Daepodong ?
不是Daepodong吗？
Maybe not
好像不是
Seoul is so big
首尔太大了
The buildings are so high
到处高楼大厦
Where's your hometown?
你家乡在哪？
Jeju-do
Jeju-do?
Never seen an islander?
从未见过岛上的人？
Nope
没
I heard it's a great place
我听说那是个号地方啊
You try living there
你想住哪
I was dying to come to Seoul
我巴不得去首尔
Seoul is not all that great
首尔不总是想象的那么好
I think everything's great
我说好就好
Apgujung-dong is nice, too
Apgujung-dong 也很不错
So, your parents are still in Jeju-do?
是吗，你父母还在Jeju-do?
My dad is. Mom passed away
我爸爸还在。我妈妈去世了。
I'm staying at my dad's friend's place
我和我爸爸的朋友住一块
Sorry
对不起
Why're you sorry?
何以抱歉？
It's not like Mom died cuz of you
我母亲去世和你没关系
My dad passed away when I was young
我很小的时候父亲去世了
My friends say sorry, too. For what!
我朋友也说对不起。为什么！
I know!
我理解
It's cuz they don't know what to say
因为他们不知道如何安慰你
Right
是的
Wanna listen?
注意听？
Whose song is this?
谁唱的歌？
Don't know Jean Ram-whe ?
不是道Jean Ram-whe?
'Etude of Memory'
Great song, isn't it?
爱丽丝的回忆，很棒，是吧？
Yeah
没错
- Wanna borrow it?
- 想拿去听听不？
- Really?
- 真的，可以吗？
If you're good
如果你听话的话
I don't know
我不知道
This isn't it, either
这也不是
What don't you like about it!
你不讨厌它什么地方
I'm not sure. Just feels unfamiliar
不清楚，就是觉得不太像
Of course it does! It's new!
它当然是真的，最新出的
How about enlarging it?
生意调大点吧？
Maybe that's why she doesn't feel familiar with it
估计就是因为这个所以听不出来
Don't get rid of the house
不要影响邻居
Just fix it up
就调大声点而已
Enlarge a house that small?
扩大了还这么小
You know, renovations
翻新的，你懂
Just repair it?
只是重修了一下啊？
Then, what do you need me for?
还有什么可以为你服务的？
Will that cut costs?
可以打折不？
Forget it!
想得美！
I have a say, don't I!
我就随口一说
How about enlarging it this way?
这样扩大一点如何？
Expand out front as much as possible
尽可能开拓视野
Turn this into one big room
八折变成一个大房子
Put in a kitchen here
这里弄个厨房
Then, the front yard
这样的话
will become the new living room
前院就可以变成一个新的卧室
Does it feel more familiar?
这样是不是更舒适些？
I think it's good
我觉得可以
What do you think?
你有何高见？
If the client likes it, I like it
顾客是上帝，你说了算
How may I help you?
有什么可以效劳的吗？
I came to look at ties
我看看领带
These are our new F/W ties
这些是我们的新款F/W领带
Over here
那边
I asked her to come
我叫她过来看看
Eun-chaehelped a lot
挺实惠的
Can I join in?
可以试试吗？
Of course, have a seat
当然，随便坐
Should we order?
有什么推荐的吗？
The wines good here
How long will the construction take?
Probably about two months
If you don't change the design
So, aren't you dating?
Want me to introduce someone?
What kind of women do you like?
A pretty and nice girl
That's impossible
No, it's not
Think of 10 pretty girls
and the nicest one out of them
She's the pretty and nice one
Think a girl like that would like you?
You two are so alike
Hold on
Yes, Chief
I asked Sung to hand the blueprints over
Eun-chae? Do you have a boyfriend?
I'm getting married
Really? When?
End of the year or early next year
Congratulations!
We decided recently
We're going to the States
I'll go study and hell work there
He's really lucky
to have a pretty girl like you
Isn't he?
What's so funny?
- Just talking about you
- About me?
That you're lucky
It's me, The pretty and nice girl
I said that?
What?
You two are together?
I didn't know
Why you! With a pretty girl like this
So sneaky
No one at work knows
It's a secret
But I thought you should know
I heard he met his first love in college
Do you know her?
I'm curious, but he won't tell
It was in his 1st year
Who is it? Someone I know?
O
Who is it? I'm curious
Tell us, You said she's a bitch
A tie in a place like this?
It's not for here
You can wear it when you go back home
It suits you well
Now, it looks like a house
Dad?
Why'd you start renovations
cuz of me?
Who said that?
I met our old neighbor
She told me
When I die
you could come down and live there
Then, there should be space
for a piano
Piano?
You struggled so much without a piano
when you were young
I don't play it anymore
Why waste your talent?
Let's just drop it
So, it's a bachelor?
How can we live, eat
and sleep in one room?
That's our first home?
My aunt says
East Village is a great place to live
It's close to my school, too
Come on, we talked about this
That's all I can do for now
It'll be hard at first, but
Daddy said hed help us out
Don't be so sensitive
Can't you think it over?
I give up!
Jae-wook's so lucky
I can come up with
great designs living here
Retard
A house, a car
all you need is a girl
Is this your new computer?
It's a Pentium with 1GB hard drive
1GB?
1,000 mega bites?
You can't use all that in your whole life
What's this?
Hey!
It's easy
Make a girl drink beer and get her drunk
Then what?
Then
you carry her and put her on a bed. That's it
- So, the stockings are...
- Hey!
Just eat your noodles
Is your club fun?
- Why?
- Just curious
You know Seo-yeun? She's in it, too
Who?
The music major in Architecture 101
That girl? She's pretty
Really? I didn't notice
She's not bad
When girls like her
start wearing makeup in second year
they get really pretty
You don't know shit
Is her boyfriend in the club, too?
The stockings are hers?
- Hey!
- What?
Don't eat all the radish you pig
HEY
Why're you here?
I forgot my keys
Look in my bag
Okay, thanks
Did you eat? Have some soup
OKHY
Come on
Just lend it to me for a few days
Go back to your store!
Come on
- Going straight home?
- Yeah
- You're all grown up
- Bye
Go on home
- Come on
- I said, no!
Seung-min!
- On your way home?
- Yeah
What are you doing here?
Came to get something
- It's heavy
- Right
- Did you eat?
- Yeah
I mean, not yet
Great, I hate eating alone
PORK SOUP
Just go! I can't!
Do you like pork soup?
What guy can't eat pork soup?
Such a city boy
I just don't like it much,
that's all
Tada!
I cleaned it over the weekend
Mopped it and everything
It's my house now
I even planted flowers
In the fall? What flowers?
Curious?
I'm not telling
I went to Jae-wooks house recently
It was really nice
Have you been there?
No. Why would I?
He said
you're really popular in the club
Of course!
Then...
you must have a boyfriend
Nope
- Go bring some soil
- Sure
Why don't you have a boyfriend?
What about you?
Well, no
See? You, too
Jae-wook is the most popular
All the girls in our club
have a crush on him
WhY's he so popular?
He's good looking and tall
He's rich
And he majors in architecture
I think that's cool
I'm in architecture
Oh, right
Just saying
Do you like Jae-wook, too?
Is that why youre taking our class?
Can't I like him?
Still
he doesn't have any interest in me
I have no chance
Learned to drink in college?
How's your girlfriend?
Flurry? She's fine
Flurry? That's her name?
Two pretty girls keep my mind off studying
So, I call em Flurry and Faze
Wanna meet Faze?
No high school girls for me
But Faze is in grade 9
- I know this person
- A girl?
No, a QUY
Somehow he met this girl and
Slept with her?
No, got close with her
They got close really fast
They do homework together
and talk about their family
Then
Why do you think they got close?
The hell are you saying?
Well, I mean
this guy and a girl
were complete strangers
It's you, right?
O
it's a guy I know at school
Screw you, man!
You don't know shit how to lie
So, who's the girl?
Just eat, pal
Yang Seo-yeun?
It's a nice, pretty name
First, buy a bottle of Soju
Then, go to her house
Open the bottle, then call her
When she picks up say I'm right outside,
then hang up
Hang UP?
Just hang up
Then shell get really curious
Why's he here?
Then, shell come out
But you reek of Soju
Shell get scared at first
It's totally baffling, right?
He shows up suddenly
and reeks like liquor?
Then, you go up close
Go up close?
Real close!
Then, shell be scared
and slowly back up
Then, shell go against the wall
Then, you hit the wall
with your right hand!
Shell get totally scared
What are you doing?
Then the surprise!
You don't say a word and walk off
Don't look back
The key is your back
It has to look somehow sad
Don't say anything? Thats it?
Too connotative?
Then
just say one thing
Say, I want you
'Let's live together!'
But how? I don't have a house
Stupid. You don't live
together for real
You just say it, fool
Thanks, Baffle. You're all I got
Why you little
Liking girls now.
You're all grown up, man
Seo-yeun is dang cute
- Damn pretty!
- Okay, man
- Seo-yeun!
- Shut up, fool!
Seo-yeun!
It's embarrassing, man!
Stop! Quiet!
Seo-yeun!
This isn't what I had in mind
You can't tell now
I can't tell from the blueprints
Don't need to
Everythings like you wanted
But
The room is smaller than I thought
This is big
It's 3,600 wider here
with folding windows here
The sofa goes here
The kitchens back there
I don't know what 3,600 means
and the windows seem small
Can't you take it out more?
Then you'll go into the sea!
Look
I left the roof, but raised
the ceiling 600 more
So, it'll look bigger
with the higher ceiling here
You saw it
What now?
You said it was okay already!
We can't change it!
Relax
It's good. I like it
- You said it
- I did not
- You did
- No, I didn't
- You really did
You asked me to meet you
when it first snowed that year
No way I'd say something so childish
I don't believe this!
I should've recorded it
Hold on a sec
It looked so big when I was young
But it's so small now
Everything looks small to you today?
Growing these days?
By the WHY
I'm curious
So curious today, too
Guess you are growing
You never lose, do you?
Fine. What are you curious about?
Is the bitch me?
What?
Your first love Is the bitch me?
It's not you
Like we had anything
Right. I thought so
But why do I feel like it's me? The bitch
It's weird
Why's it you?
You have a weird sense of humor
No, Mom
That's Eun-chaes opinion
Don't have to worry about it, Mom
I'm busy now
Everyone in the markets doing it
They're gonna tear it down
Just do whatever you want!
Sell your shop or not!
I gotta go
How can you talk to your mom like that?
They're redeveloping the area
around her shop
It's complicated. So annoying!
When you go to the States
she'll live there by herself?
I guess
What if she gets sick?
You should take care of her
I don't have a choice
That's why sons are no use
Treating your mom like that
What should I do?
Live there forever with her?
Grow old together and die?
I'm just worried, that's all
Why should you be?
Just visit her often
so she doesn't get lonely
Think I'm going somewhere to play?
With rent and everything
I'll hardly get by
Okay, I get it
What do you know?
You have a lot of money, time
and live alone, so you can say that
How'd you know?
That I live alone
I meant...
Just go without me
- Wait! Come on
- Stop!
It's cuz I'm damn embarrassed
Are you mad?
You and your sense of things
How'd you know that I live alone?
Cuz you never once mentioned
your husband in the designing
So, I figured you live alone
Guess it was kinda obvious
But I didn't lie from the start
We were separated
I got divorced last month
I held out as long as I could
For what?
I need the money
My lawyer said
I could get more the longer I held out
Thanks to that
I could build the house
I'm shameless, right?
A real bitch, right?
But I have no choice
It's how the world turns
That's life
Here's the Spicy Soup
Enjoy your meal
Spicy Soup
Isn't it a weird name?
If there's pork, it's Pork Soup
If there's beef, it's Beef Soup
But this is just called Spicy Soup
That's it
No matter what's in here
I don't like it
Then, we should've ordered Fish Soup
It's just
My life seems like Spicy Soup
Don't know whats in it
It's just spicy
Everything okay at work?
Something came up here
I'll go up on the first plane tomorrow
Another bottle, please!
Yeah, she's with me
It's nothing
Okay, BYE
You've had enough
Cancel the Soju, please
No, I want another bottle. You go!
You drank enough, Get up
Okay!
That's enough for today
Are you okay? Get up
Stand up
Why drink so much!
It's okay.
Rubbing alcohol will heal it fast
Stupid
Bastard
Me?
Shit! Everything's fucked!
This weeks assignment is
Where I want to live
Go someplace nice and have fun
Enjoy the weather
- Hey! Why hit so much?
- Don't know!
It's so nice
Today's my birthday
- Today?
' Yup, today
November 11th. Remember
Shouldn't you be having
a party with friends?
Aren't you my friend?
Let's have a party together
- Cheers!
What do you think
we'll be doing in 10 years?
I'll be an architect and you'll be a pianist
I'm not playing piano
Why?
I'm sick and tired of it
Know what the others call me?
Jeju-do piano school girl
What's that?
Seoul kids had private tutoring
I'm an insult to them
Only my dad's proud of me
What will you do then?
Become an announcer
I'll be a radio DJ, make money,
and become famous!
Announcers make a lot?
Don't they?
At least I can get married to someone rich
Then, I'll build a big house
in a place like this
You build it for free, okay?
Free?
Cheapskate
Here's the down payment
Happy?
I wanna live in a house like this
It'll have 2 floors
With lots of windows and a big yard
Is that too big?
This is the living room
This is the master bedroom
And I'll have two kids
So, the kids rooms go
on the second floor
And I'm going to raise a dog.
A huge one!
Woof! Woof!
And a big front entrance
I gotta pee
There's no bathroom
You keep watch
Stand far away
But not too far!
A kiss?
That's what you call a kiss?
This is a real kiss
Look
Your lips come together
Then, her lips and yours naturally come in
They slither in like snakes
They touch
Naturally, they get like this
They mix
They become one
They rub against each other
like fuckin crazy!
They go back and forth
and rap around like crazy!
Rub! Ecstasy!
That's a kiss!
What you did is just a peck.
Like you peck yo mama!
Stupid
And to a girl whos sleeping?
That's a crime, man
I'm beat
We played,
walking on railway tracks
What's that?
Don't know?
Whoever falls off
the tracks first loses
That's so lame
Listen
She says the winner
hits the loser's wrist
You don't hit wrists
unless you're close right?
You have to hold hands. Right?
What else?
Punch each others face?
He//0, campus
Fall is nearly over
I recently planted ﬂowers
in the yard
A friend asked what flowers I planted
But I didn't tell what they were
It'll be another reason
to wait and look forward to spring
Todays last song is
by Jean Ram-whe
'Etude of Memory'
Did you hear me on the air?
I did
How was it?
Your voice sounded great
HEY
What are you doing here?
The bus would've been fine
It's okay
seniors can drive juniors home
He's sleeping so comfortably
Are you close with him?
Well, a little
Then, good luck with him
No way. We're not like that
Look at his shirt
GUESS starts with G,U,E
The spellings wrong
That's so fake
Oh, it is!
G, E, U...
Jae-wook?
How much is the place you live in?
Why? Thinking of moving?
Yes, my dad told me to look into it
Really?
Another member to the Ritz then?
The Ritz? What's that?
Nickname for the most
expensive area of Seoul
Come by my apartment to
look around and stuff
I'll buy you drinks
Really? Can I come over?
Of course, anytime
When do you wanna come?
Anytime you're available
- I'll get off here
- What?
- Take care. See ya
- Hey!
What's with him running off like that?
So? How about this weekend?
Sure, anytime
Saturday's good
You're home?
Where'd I put the Aspirin?
My head kills
What are you doing!
What's with you today?
Can't we move, Mom?
Move?
To like an apartment in the Ritz area?
What the hell are you talking about!
You earn the money and move if you want
Throw that shirt out!
Why! It's fine!
Why you! Got money
coming out of your ears?
When I only sold $20 worth today!
Okay, okay!
Can't you stop saying that?
$20! Again?
Man
Why that little!
Damn kid
Just break it why don't you!
He must be out of his mind!
There's only one thing left to do
Just tell her
HQW?
Ask her to meet on the first day of snow
That's saying I like her?
She could think it doesn't mean anything
What women would think that?
Then, shed be a bear
If so, it won't be worth dating the bitch
Who're you calling bitch?
Forget it, man
I'm teaching aesthetics to a guy
who can't even do factoring
Forget it, man!
Fine!
I give UP
What! You didn't even do anything!
I just want Seo-yeun to be happy
That's it
Hal9I9Y? Happiness?
What the hell?
Wait
are there 2 Ps or 1 in happiness?
Can't be 3
Give me one
No way, man. This is for adults
Give me one!
Try asking nicely, man!
Here
Take a drag, then blow
A drag?
Suck in the smoke, then gulp it down!
What the hell?
Damn
My precious smoke!
Is it heavy?
No, I like lifting heavy things
We're almost there
That's my place
Be honored
You're the first guest to my house
Are you happy to move here?
Of course. It's my own place
And it's in the Ritz as they say
Wanna see pics?
Look!
I grew a lot
This my dad
This is me
This is my house in Jeju-do
- This?
- Yeah
See? I'm the tallest
I used to play a lot with these friends
I can go back by myself
It's okay
I'll walk you to the bus stop
You don't know your way around
You don't know this area
Now, we can't take
the same bus anymore
Complete opposite ends
I kinda got attached to that neighborhood
What are you doing
on the first day of snow?
What? When's that?
Well, I'm not sure...
When winter comes?
Do you wanna meet up?
Soundsfun
Let's meet
in the empty house
on the first day it snows
Okay?
Well, okay
Promise!
I'm Mr.Yang Sang-yun's daughter
He suddenly had blood pressure
problems and got worse
Is he okay now?
He's stabilized for now
Well have to wait for
the CT scan results tomorrow
- Hello
- Hi
You came?
What are you doing?
Errands
I love the basalt in the yard
Can we put more in?
It's perfect as is. No more
Let's just eat
PIANO SCHOOL
Know this place?
I started taking piano here
It's still the same
Let's go eat. Aren't you hungry?
Why're you dying to eat?
Starve yourself?
I wanna buy you seaweed soup
For what?
For your birthday
It's November 11th, isn't it?
What?
I'm wrong?
Did you change your birthday?
No. It's my birthday
Then, what?
Cuz you're cute and sweet
Where's my present?
This is it?
Sea urchin in seaweed tastes really good
There's something I want
I've never tasted anything like this
Can I say it?
What is it this time?
I need a room for a piano
I gave it a lot of thought
I'm going to settle down here
My dad
The hospital can't do much for him now
He has 1 or 2 years left
It's not a long time
Spending that time with him
I think it'll be good
So, I won't regret it
And I wanna take the time
to reset my life
Start fresh. Cool, huh?
For real?
Yes
Are you crazy?
I don't get that woman!
It's going to be done next week!
Is she kidding?
She says shell pay
all additional costs
Money's not everything
It'll take a month to redesign it
What about our schedule?
Next months our wedding!
I told you
She wants to settle there
That's her problem!
I won't do it
I can't
Just hand it over to me
You get ready for the wedding
No, I'll do it
I'll finish it
Let me do this
We can't expand it any bigger by law
So, let's put the piano here
What about my room?
We'll put it upstairs
Make it into a two-story house
You'll get hurt
Don't worry, I won't
I'm scared of getting hurt cuz of you
The depth should be 30cm
for enough light to come in
It has to look good
so please be extra careful with this
- Enjoy your meal
- Thank you!
Wanna go around again?
I meant 150 with the finishings
We gotta do it again
The movers are coming on the 28th
E verythings going b y boat so its crazy
Take things slowly
Thanks for listening to
my boring lectures all semester
Feel more familiar with architecture now?
- Yes
- Class is over
There's an after-party
Hope you all stop by for drinks
Dismissed!
Jae-wook?
I heard you moved
Not too long ago
Then, let's stop by the party
and I'll drive you home
But have you seen Seung-min today?
Seung-min? No
I can't be friends anymore
My mind, my heart won't allow...
Damn!
It's freezing
I like you
That's it
Where are you?
Why aren't you answering?
Page me when you hear this Okay?
Recorded
What are you doing here?
Nothing
Here
But I can't really drink
Me, neither
Seo-yeun? Are you okay?
We're here
Seo-yeun? Can you walk?
Seo-yeun?
You Okay?
Let's go in first
Is this it?
Down here?
Careful
Where're you headed?
Huh?
Jeongneung
I can't go there
WW not?
I can't go north of the river
at this hour
Let's go
No, I can't
Close the door
Go to Jeongneung
- Fuck! Let's go!
- Fuck?
Crazy little bastard
What did you just say? Fuck?
Go home quietly if you're drunk kid
Go to Jeongneung!
Get away!
- Son of a bitch!
- Go to Jeongneung!
Who'd go that far at this hour!
Crazy son of a bitch!
Go to Jeongneung!
Why you little!
Get away!
That bitch!
That stupid bitch!
Forget her
She's not the only girl
Forget a bitch like that!
When I go to college next year
I'll look after ya
But
Just cuz they went in together
that doesn't mean anything happened
He could've just took her home
cuz she's drunk
I'll bring Flurry and Faze over
We'll meet on the first day of snow
And have a double date
We'll have snowball fights
and make snowmen
Slapping wrists, too!
Doesn't that sound awesome?
Seung-min?
Cheer up, pal
This way, please
You're here?
All done
When are you completely
moving down here?
As soon as Dad gets out of
the hospital
It's all finished, huh?
All over
How do you feel?
It was good to build this
I'm glad I did it
And you?
How do you feel?
Not sure
You didn't like it?
You made a promise
to build my house
Remember?
Tell me
Why were you so nice to me then?
Because I liked you
Now, you tell me?
It took long enough
You knew?
Think I'm stupid?
Of course I knew
You even kissed me
When I was asleep
That was my first kiss
It's late. I'd better go
OKHY
Take care
Bye
Want me to move this?
No, I'll do it later
It's not much
Where do you want it?
It's okay. I'll do it
Why'd you come to me?
Anyone could've built your house
Why'd you come to me now?
I was curious
What?
How you're living
How you are now
I was curious
That's it?
Just cuz you're curious?
That's why you had this all this time?
Yes
That's why I had it
Why can't I hold on to it?
When you're...
You were my first love
I called many times
But you never answered
I don't have a CD player
I can't listen to it
And don't call me anymore
Why?
Just don't
What do you mean?
Now...Get out of my life
- How's this?
- Hmm?
This is better, isn't it?
I think it's better, too
I must've gained weight.
It feels tight
Doesn't it look too racy?
It's suffocating
Suffocating? Where?
It's so stuffy I feel like
I'm going to die
How can I help you?
Wanna go for a walk?
- I want to go home
- What?
I want to go home
Okay, let's go home Dad
It's all built
We can go and live there
Wanna see pictures?
This is the living room
and the master bedroom
And here...
Who's this?
He's just
A friend
Pork Soup?
For old time sake
You can't eat that in the States
Should I just stay, Mom?
What the hell are you saying?
You'll be alone. I'm worried
Shut up and cut the nonsense
Fool
Here
It's my wedding gift. Use it
That's for selling your shop
Move to an apartment with it!
Live comfortably for once!
I forgot the Kimchi
Where's my head?
Don't worry about me
Just be good to your wife
Not again
I lived here for over 30 years
Expect me to go someplace new
at my age?
I'm gonna live here till I die
Don't say that!
You're not gonna die
If you get old, you die
Aren't you sick of this place?
You struggled your whole life here
Why would I be sick of it?
A home is a home
Why's it so hard to open?
- I'm gonna take a nap
- Okay
You're playing a little fast
Let's practice it 10 more times
- Okay
- Ready?
Have a good day
- See you tomorrow
- Bye
Dad, let's go in. It's cold
It's okay
I love this
Anyone home?
' Yang s e°'Ye _ Yes? Un?
Sign here, please
Thank you
FROM.' LEE SEUNG-MIN
TO.' YANG 5EO- YEUN